The words were also like, "I did this
research." So, like not only was this
person stealing your report, but they
were also claiming to do research they
didn't do?
>> That's hilarious.
What's the point of hacking when you can
just, you know, critical thing, right?
All right, y'all. We've talked about
ThreatLocker ring-fencing a lot. We know
how it allows you to set ACLs and
policies for exactly what an application
is allowed to do in your network. But
today I'm going to tell you how it does
that, okay? Three technologies:
minifilter drivers, Windows Filtering
Platform, and EX Version kernel
notification routines. Minifilter
drivers are essentially a hook or
callback for um IO requests, okay? So,
when you're trying to write or read from
a file, you can create a hook with those
and approve or deny based off of the
ThreatLocker ACL. Windows Filtering
Platform, similar situation but for
connect bind uh requests, right? You can
say, "Okay, hey, is this process allowed
to talk to port 443 over there on the
internet?" Yes or no. Approve or deny.
Lastly, you've got EX Version kernel
notification routines. The EX Version is
important because uh it allows you to
approve or deny versus just getting a
notification from the kernel.
Um and this is specific for um hooking
various native API calls like NT Create
User Process, which is what you'd use to
like spin up powershell.exe or something
like that. Okay? So, those three are
very useful to ThreatLocker's
ring-fencing core technology. Hope you
enjoyed learning how this is
implemented. Check out ThreatLocker if
you think you would benefit from
something like that. All right, let's go
back to the show.
What's up, hackers? We got the This Week
in Bug Bounty segment where we do
rapid-fire news. This week we've got two
entries. One is uh the Bug Bounty
Maturity Framework from HackerOne, which
is not the Bug Bounty Maturity Framework
we mentioned last week, which is from
Steve Hernandez. Um so, don't get those
two confused. There's been a lot of
chatter in the world right now about um
quantifying where you are if you're a
Bug Bounty Program Manager and where
your program is at where how it's
performing. Um and this is another tool
for that. So, uh HackerOne breaks this
up into three maturity tiers: baseline,
competitive, and exemplary.
Um and they put this together with
feedback from HackerOne's advisory board
and technical advisory board. Um hacker
advisory board and technical advisory
board.
So, really good to see. Hopefully, we'll
see programs starting to look at these
frameworks and getting clear steps for
improving their program, whether you use
the HackerOne Maturity Framework or the
Bug Bounty Maturity Framework that we
mentioned last week.
Um next up is uh a job posting actually
on our job site. You can find that at
jobs.ctbb.show.
And this is a posting for a product
security analyst by Integrity. Um so, if
you're looking to hop in with the
platform, uh it's fully uh you know,
remote-friendly. Uh so, that's great to
see and it's a great way for you to get
integrated with the community uh in at
large if you're looking for a position.
All right, that's it. Let's go to the
show.
Hey, what's up everyone? Today, I'm here
with our guest, Valery. We've got a
couple cool things to uh talk about, but
uh he is a long-time hacker and I'm
going to make him jump straight into a
bug before I introduce him. But, uh
yeah, so what bug did you bring us?
Actually, when you mentioned that I need
to bring something, I was like really
like shocked because that came to my
desk 30 minutes before the podcast
almost. And I was like, "Okay, like what
can I share?" Like I have a tons of
things and usually it's like really
interesting things. I don't waste my
time on average like findings, like
medium. I usually do something really
extreme exciting and yeah, that cannot
be duplicated from somebody. So, the
first thing that came to my my mind was
the issue when I discovered that
the company So, that's the field of the
acquisition when the company have the
wide scope range and they're okay if you
hack them through the acquired assets.
And there is a a few programs in
HackerOne specially where you can do
these things. In other places, you might
be really in a trouble, I would say.
Um so, yeah, think twice before making
this.
And so, I did the the kind of the recon.
I did the investigation of what the
company is planning to acquire and I did
kind of the preparation of the possible
acquisition. So, I discover the company
itself wasn't acquired yet. And it was
announced in the news, but the legal
part of the acquisition had like wasn't
happened before.
Um so, I did the preparation and I
suddenly discovered an issue with the
Node.js path reversal to the server like
information. And I was like, "Okay, like
that's interesting. I cannot submit this
right now and that's kind of like not
really exciting finding because I cannot
escalate it to something critical."
And I was like, I just waited with my
like notes
for the final part of the acquisition
process and when it happened,
uh before the before the day of the
final day, I checked the bug. The bug
was legit. It worked well and I did the
screenshots and I was like in the way of
making the screenshots, I was like,
"What if I can escalate it to something
because somebody can ask me like, 'What
if like what does it mean for us? Like
what is does it mean for us as a
business? Like what is the risk?'" And I
usually like to expose the risk
immediately like without arguing. That's
like you know that's a server side. It
should be like uh legit. It should be
rated as a high or a critical. I don't
like to to play this game. I just
straightforward with the with the
business risks. So, I checked the
environment variables uh self in the run
and other files where the environment
variables could be placed.
And I discovered one place where it was
some AWS credentials and and and other
interesting stuff. So, the next day the
acquisition happened and I was like,
"Okay, let me report this finally
because it's kind of prepared, it's
working well."
And when I did the the replication of
the steps, I realized that the server
doesn't work at all. Like, it's
completely shut it down.
And I was like, "Damn." Like, and the
the the possible the possible bounty of
that story was from 10 to 12,000. I was
like, "Damn." Like, the the issue just
burned to the ashes. Like, what can I do
with this?" But I was like kind of lucky
and smart at the same time. I checked
the screenshot that I made and I checked
the credentials that I took from the
screenshots. And from the screenshot
with this heavily long like AWS
credentials, I replicate to my CLI
uh and validate the credentials. And the
credentials was legit.
And I was like, "Okay." So, that's like
they weren't they weren't expired yet?
They wasn't expired. They wasn't
rotated. Even it was like the server was
like shut it down, it was the
credentials for the core system that was
was probably wired from the company
itself and it worked like to the with
access to the database, to the AWS, and
cetera.
I was like, "Okay." Like, as Jason
Haddix says, like, there is no places
where just the finding could be like
legit for very long period of time. It
could be legit as like as a short term
as well. So, that was like the brilliant
example when you can find something, it
was like like really working well for a
few seconds. Maybe you did the
screenshot and the rest is like is like
nothing happened
extra later. So, I did the validation
part, I did the screenshots, and the
triage asked me like, "Dude, like, it
doesn't work." Like, and I was like,
"You know, but the part of the
credential is still working and it's
still like important to investigate this
story fully because that was exposed,
that was the evidence of the exposure,
the credentials work well, it is still
working, I have still access to the
database. Like, you need to do something
with this, right?" So,
um they acknowledged that
facts, I would say.
And yeah, the the issue was accepted and
paid well, like 12 or maybe 10 and 1/2
thousand, yeah. And I was like really
like amazed of that and I used this as a
great evidence. Um if somebody asking me
like, "You know, it doesn't work right
now, but if it was legit before and I
said the credentials was legit, if the
exposure was legit, like it doesn't
matter." I would say.
Um and I even did the article in the
medium and it get and it became viral, I
would say. Um I just I used this like
very very like
um hyped words in the title saying like,
"10K for the vulnerability that doesn't
exist." Um yeah, so that was the story.
Um and another
Yeah. Yeah, sure. I think I think that
that Well, I just love that that's such
a like uh
a key example of why you really have to
document everything. I try to tell new
hunters all the time because a lot of
people get frustrated with triage not
being able to replicate things or, you
know, things going down cuz right now
especially, there's like some really
long triage times. Oh, and even if there
is fast triage, by the time it gets to
the program, it feels like it's a lot
longer. I think AI is impacting that a
little bit, but a video POC is just like
the best thing you can do because one,
you can prove it was working. Two, you
can obviously pause it frame by frame
for any like thing that's exposed or any
data that you've exposed. You know, you
you still have usually the re- requests
and responses inside of Caido or inside
of Burp. And so, yeah, I think it's like
really important that you document your
findings because like you said, those
credentials were active and exposed and
they have no idea until they go and do
the actual incident response or you
know, look into who accessed it and how,
you know, whether they need to rotate it
or not.
Um let me add something to this story. I
think the the new business that is
coming to this field, they didn't know
how the process should look like from
the company perspective. And as a
security engineer on my full-time work,
I understand this and I learned that's
like attack surface, the investigation
part, what should be investigated and
when and how. And like I use this
knowledge against other companies, I
would say um as a bug hunter because I
knew, okay, that was critical, that was
exposure. You need to investigate this,
you can't deny on this. So yeah.
Yeah, that's true. And honestly, I mean,
you can actually legitimately even just
say that in your reports, like, hey, I
manage other programs. I know how this
works. You all need to dig into this and
do a do an incident or do, you know, do
a do a response into figure out, you
know, was this accessed by external
entities? How many people had access?
How long was it exposed? Like that sort
of thing.
Yeah. So um I know that you I told I
whenever I mentioned this, you said you
had a several that came to mind. Do you
want to mention one more bug before we
move on? Yeah, yeah. The second one is
also like nice and I can even reference
the previous guest from the podcast.
Matias Karlsson was in the podcast some
years ago, I think, right? He just came
back from his
retirement.
And he was in the podcast and he shared
kind of cool stuff that is underrated, I
would say. So he he said, when you open
the Burp and when you work with the with
the scope items, everything that is in
your Burp history might be the scope
items as well, even if it's not really
listed well in the scope surface and the
the scope list.
And if the the company itself, if the
program itself is kind of okayish to
have
like interesting parts discover here and
there. You might work with this broad
really attack surface
to discover very
useful and interesting parts and stuff.
So, the story happened pretty much the
same with me. I did the investigation I
did the research for one of the company
from the HackerOne platform.
And I I was familiar with the platform
with the program. I really recognized
that they really appreciate my effort by
bringing the attention to the critical
things. And I was like, "Okay, like let
me go like deeper. Like what if I will
do something extra?" So, I did like
processed
I don't want to expose the name of the
organization and the the the technical
part, but I I I did the process as a
user. Like I did something as a user and
I realized that in one page there was
the terms and conditions link. And the
link was really different what I saw
from the name of the URL. That was the
link to to some agency I would say.
And I was like, "Hold on, like I'm doing
this stuff for that organization and it
should in the text itself it's the text
from that organization kind of, but the
link is from the other domain like that
is that is not really connected. From
the whois you cannot like differentiate
like you can really literally
differentiate it's it's a different
organization." And I was like, "What if
this agency work for that company and do
something for them? Like literally." And
I did this like with the with the
products that they offer.
And I was like, "Okay, let me check this
agency slightly without digging too deep
without breaking some rules and like
making me like harmful as a hacker.
So, I checked I did the basic recon and
I discovered the Symphony
uh, mode
uh, enabled.
And from the Symfony, I was able to go
deeper to the environment variables with
the PHP info of that,
uh, application. And in PHP info, it was
the credentials to something else. And I
was like, "Hold on, like, I'm not really
sure that I'm hacking to the right way.
Like, what if I will break the rules
and, yeah,
um, the terms of the usage of that
service?"
And I checked one more thing before
going deeper. I checked another place
where the log file was exposed. And the
log file in another domain of that
organization says, like, the log file
itself was like kind of useless. You
cannot do anything with this. But the
log log file literally says how they're
working with the organization that I
used before. They like doing some kind
of content management, I would say,
uh, doing some like upload files, etc. I
was like, "Okay, that's legit. That
organization connected to the production
where I just saw that link." So, I
I checked the credentials.
Um,
it it gave me the access to the
to the WordPress admin panel where
they're doing this management part for
that organization. And I was able, as a
user with these credentials, to change
the content of that first organization.
>> Nice.
Yeah. And I was like, "Okay, that's
that's like that's kind of dumb, but
it's interesting because I was able to
change anything with the stored XSS,
with the content itself."
>> And I was like, "What if they do this as
well on the main domain?" Because I
discovered that from the organizational
one. And what if the the main
organization have this in the main
domain, right? So, I checked and I found
the the the the path with a with a the
login with a login to the WordPress. And
I reused these credentials to get into
the main domain of that organization and
it worked well. So, the suppliers did
their work, but they did with this that
work not really smart enough to use
different credentials for the different
environments,
uh, for the different applications.
And yeah, I was able to to jump so far
out of scope to bring the items from the
out of scope to the in scope and it was
so heavy, organization just immediately
like broke the rule broke the the
application itself, stopped the the
service that service, changed
everything. Um, but the fun part is like
that's legit story when the supplier can
hit you hardly, like and you should as
an organization, you should do your your
own due diligence due due diligence uh,
before working with this organization,
right?
Uh, another part uh, that is really
interesting for me was um,
that that WordPress admin was on the
very well-known brand. And if I would
tell you like later after the podcast
saying like, "Look, I I got the admin
access of the WordPress of that
organization." You might be very
surprised saying like, "No way they have
WordPress on the main domain."
But the story is they're doing the
microservices integration to from the
from the old domains to the main domain
through their proxy.
And you see like kind of the link, but
technically that's a proxy embedding the
content from the different domain and
from the different like really like
scope of the domains with the
applications with the technologies.
And
as I said before like Matias panels was
kind of smart saying like, "That's my
the deal the your scope items itself by
probably the the application." So, that
might happen. And for me from that
story, it's kind of the question every
time when the when the triages saying
like, "Look guy,
uh, that's not listed in the scope,
right?" But with this complex situation
when everybody might work with a
different microservices, with
integrations, with a proxies, how can
you like say like if it's legit or not?
Like, you can only like guess, I think.
Yeah.
But, that story is really like important
to to to mention once again, like, don't
go too deep before like doing something.
Like, you should like summarize and
think twice before like kind of breaking
the rules, I would say. Yeah, yeah. No,
I think the fact that you found that log
file is like hilarious and cool because
you basically were able to like know for
a fact that they were using this pro-
provider for their,
you know, third-party management of
their
um of their CMS or whatever it was. But,
um
yeah, no, it also reminds me I had a
very very similar finding, actually. Um
I was working with Eric uh Today's New,
and he had found like a leaked Google
Doc, like Google Drive or a Google
Sheets link that had a whole bunch of
like hard-coded usernames and passwords
um for a bunch of Drupal websites.
And it was the same exact thing. A major
company had hired um you know, some sort
of like content or marketing firm to
basically manage all of their Drupal
instances.
And so, then they had just put all the
username and passwords for all of those
Drupal websites,
which were in scope, you know, like the
the company that we reported this to was
like, you know, star. you know,
example.com. And these was a whole bunch
of like marketing pages for that were
that were on that domain. And so, it was
in scope, but basically the third-party
marketing company had exposed all of
those credentials. And you could just
straight-up log in and then use the
Drupal
um there's like a in some Drupal
instances, you can just get RCE
immediately on the server.
And so, it was like I don't know, it was
like it was like RCE across a bunch of
different uh sites.
Um and I absolutely think that what you
reported was in scope, right? I mean,
you could manage the content for that
main thing. And I'm not surprised at all
that they were using WordPress under the
hood because I'm sure you see this all
the time. Whenever I'm looking at major
companies, it feels like 90% of them
somehow have like Adobe AEM
that like tied in with a bunch of other
microservices on their main domain. It
seems like so many companies, even
though under the hood it's like also a
Next.js app or something else, they're
still like all the content seems to like
come from like all of the static
resources still somehow route through
AEM. Like that's true for LinkedIn,
which is like super weird, right? As
like a large company you would think
they would have their own thing. Um
so it doesn't surprise me at all that
they were using WordPress under the
hood. Now, that's a really that's a
really cool finding, man.
Appreciate.
All right, so one thing I wanted to
mention here was
um also, do you pronounce your handle
Kravets Co?
Yeah, that's right.
Okay, cool. Yeah, so um his handle is
Kravets Co. Um so on X he's Kravets Co
Valeriy. And anyways, we'll put the
links in the show notes, but
his uh
his stats, just if in case anybody's
wondering, just over the last 90 days on
HackerOne are a 7.0 signal and a 41
impact score, which is in the 98th
percentile. So, like he said, he's
basically only reporting highs and
criticals. Um
so yeah, I had a question. Do you are do
you farm a specific program? Like do you
have some anchor programs or do you kind
of like just look across a bunch
different stuff? Like what's what's your
game plan when it comes to doing bug
bounty? Because obviously you have a
full-time job as a as a program manager
as well. Yeah, um actually the
statistics might be greater because the
program when I did this cool stuff just
made a pause saying we have too much to
to to make. That's the very big
technical backlog. So, we are pausing
the entire program because kind of me
maybe and other hackers that were there.
So, yeah, and I have a few things in my
draft. Uh so, when they will come back
to the program uh and unpause this, I
have something to surprise them. Um
actually actually let me let me comment
right there. It feels to me like that's
a second indicator
of you being very prepared. So, like you
know, if I'm being honest, I think
you know, all of us have heuristics for
things. And I think that like my
heuristic for understanding who you are
as a hacker, the fact that one, you were
like prepping for the acquisition, and
then the fact that here you have you
literally have draft reports ready to
submit, makes me like see how like
how prepared you are basically. Like you
know what I mean? As a hacker, you are
optimizing, and I think this is really
key cuz like you know, in my personal
success when I first got started, the
only way I was able to find bugs in this
like sea of people who are much more
talented was by being like slightly
faster than them, right? The instant I
would get a new invite, I would just
like hack on it for 2 hours and like run
all the things and try to get a report
in because I knew I wasn't smarter than
a lot of the hackers at that point in
time. And so, I knew I had to win by
speed. And so, it feels like you are,
you know, kind of optimizing in a
similar way.
Um, and and it comes through like you
basically being prepared, which is
really cool.
I would say controversial.
I'm kind of lazy and I'm doing my
homework just to have my time and my
like rest time on my sofa. So, I'm I I'm
doing this homework, yeah, just to save
my time in the future.
But, that's never ending story. I'm
working working working, yeah. It might
feel like I'm really concentrated and
prepared, but technically when I'm
getting some results, financial results
for the year or like statistics results
from the reputation score, I'm kind of
trying to be chill. Like usually it
happens from the August or from the
September, like when the all goals that
I put on my desk achieved. And I was
like, "Okay, like let's do some fun
stuff like uh riding snowboard, riding
the surfboard,
um anything I want, yeah, without
focusing on security especially."
Yeah. Um, so let me go back
>> to my question. So did you say you do
have anchor programs or
How do you handle that? Like that's kind
of the my like I'm doing this first
first of all I'm doing that part of
hacking on that way because I just want
to be with high success rate of each
submission. I didn't want to waste my
time on the duplicate on the
questionable reports where the
the impact might be in question from the
program management side.
I do this specifically
with the yeah as you said with the
highly critical that's the three
success.
When I'm doing this I'm trying to find
my passion. I can't like force myself to
the specific direction hacking to the
coinbase hacking to the something like
really hard programs where everybody was
there
I would say. So I'm trying to find my
passion first with the leaderboards of
the private programs. Okay, I got the
invitation to the private program. That
private program is on on a platform for
at least three years already. Let's
check who is in the leaderboard. Okay,
NahamSec. Okay, Justin. Let's beat that
guys with the
findings with the statistics.
And that's kind of the part of the
motivation from my side. How can I like
stick on that program?
If the program was really old I'm trying
to check what the activity statistics
was. Were there like really a lot of
findings before or they just wasting the
time on the contract paying to the
HackerOne without really profitable bugs
because that might happen. So if I see
this I was like okay, that's my time.
Let's make the rock and roll. Let's
surprise the program.
And that happened a few times. Even my
friend he worked in one company
and I got the invitation and the program
was old. I was like okay like there is a
guy there is a Ben in the leaderboard.
Let's do some something interesting and
I got the third place I I say
in the entire leaderboard history. And a
friend of mine once
once shared with me, not the private
message, but the
the feedback from the development team
when I discovered another critical
findings. And I was like, okay, like the
people really amazed of my work. And it
kind of feel for me to bring more.
So, I'm trying to to work on the
programs where I see that appreciation,
I would say. Yeah. And when the company
even commenting the findings with the
human text, that in our days it's rare.
Like, usually they just use the
predefined answers or AI responses. When
I see the human interaction, I was like,
okay, like, dude, like, that's amazing.
Like, I will I would like to work with
you more, so I'll submit more. Um, yeah,
that's kind of the passion. And the the
biggest part is I want to have
attachment to the well-known brands. So,
I'm I'm choosing the programs where they
connected to the
health, to the connect connected to the
sport, connected to the finance. And,
like, making the beer time with my
friend, I could say, dude, like, I just
hacked them. Like, without exposing
anything, I can like say that. Yeah, of
course.
>> Yeah, that's really cool. Yeah, man, a
couple things there. One, I definitely
agree. Like, when there is a human on
the other side that I respect and like
and can tell they like like and respect
me. Like, I'm going to throw out some
random names, like Roy from John Deere
and like Hugs for Bugs from Capital One.
Like, when I see those things, like, I
legitimately get way more excited and
invested in actually hacking on them. I
think it's funny that you
that you use for motivation, like,
bypassing other top hackers on the
leaderboard for specific privates. I
think that's a really that's a really
like cool funny motivation.
In fact, I think you messaged me. I
would love to for you to share just real
quick what motivates you to get into bug
about cuz I think it's cool. And just
the way that like your little goals have
like stacked up over time.
Yeah, that's true. Yeah, the fun part
started like with the first submission
to the PayPal with my friend. And before
that submission, I did the the research
for fun. Like it was not my really like
them and concentration. I did this for
fun. I was like curious about how this
stuff working, how this IoT devices
working, how this web applications
working when I'm using this web
applications.
And I practiced kind of on the real
targets.
And one day the friend of mine
mined a lot of submissions critical or
the high with a great payouts on the
PayPal. And I was like, "Okay, what that
dude is doing? Like I kind of knew him,
but not really well. Let's Let's check
like who is here, like what he's doing,
like maybe to collaborate." And he he
knew me before from my social media
activities, from Medium, from other
places.
And he was like, "You know, dude, like I
really trust you. Like what if you can
like help me to to make more
more stuff on that target that I
hooked." And he shared with me the part
of the target that where he mined the
vulnerability before. It was like three
vulnerability reports with a CVE-9
on the PayPal. And I was like, "Okay,
like that's interesting. Let Let me
figure out what it is." And I realized
that
when he did the submission, they patched
the submission not in the chain of the
CVE. They patched this like with a with
a specific chain that can kind of
breaking the CVE itself. So, I found the
bypass, and we did it again together.
>> Nice. And my first My first bounty was
6K. Like I was really amazed. Like you
know
>> That's insane. I was You'll be I would
be curious to know what like most
people's are. Mine was 750.
750. Yeah, I was literally
Um I might be happy with the 300, with
the 200, but with the 6K I was like,
holy moly, like what is going on? And
that story Did you have Did you have
anybody in your life that was like
shocked by that? Like did you Were you
young and like told your parents? Or did
you have a girlfriend that you told that
was like mind-blown?
No, I was like really like already kind
of mature.
I had I had a wife. Uh we got a kid. And
I was like, you know, like I just saved
uh our rental payments for the next like
4 months is 5 months is
>> Wow. Uh and I was like like kind of that
feeling of fresh air, like kind of spin
that wheel.
Uh and I I from that time I started
constantly spinning this wheel because
of the gamification of the platform, I
would say. Like you see this
leaderboard, you see this statistic, you
see the that uh stick
um
pictures. You like, okay, like um I was
lazy on that month. Let me find
something. And each month I'm doing this
like for how many years? I think more
than six, I think. All right, dude.
Thank you for all of the all of the tips
and all of the like insane uh bugs that
you've already shared. But now I want to
get to like the main reason we were
bringing you on. Uh for for our
listeners, this is actually like really
really interesting to me because
uh well, first let me let me broach the
topic. The The topic is basically that
Valerie had some report / research
stolen through bug bounty.
And um I'm going to let him kind of lay
it out here in a minute, but I think
this is like very very interesting
because of the the way that it happened.
And you know, we've known in the past,
hey, if you submit a vulnerability
through HackerOne, there's always like a
tiny chance that Hacker like the
HackerOne triage that sees it might take
it. You know, HackerOne punishes that
and is very um serious about it, but
there's always a chance. And then also
we've seen examples of program managers
or triagers for programs taking research
and running with it, but this is kind of
something that's neither one of those
and is pretty interesting. And so,
Valerie, you actually I'm going to stop
calling you Valerie. I'm going to start
calling you hacker handle cuz I always
like being called Res on here. So,
Kurbatko,
you know, you you reported a bug back in
and it was more of like
an entirely like new research attack
vector that you're not really willing to
share yet, but then tell us what
happened kind of after that. Yeah,
well, I think it's kind of kind kind of
it's important to share that it was the
attack surface. Like it was not the
vulnerability, it was not the tiny
vulnerability because I shared that
story with my friend and the friend said
like, well, like some people might steal
your XSS attack payload. Like why don't
you like
care about this?
And but that on that time it was the the
attack vector itself and it was harmful
attack vector because
before that, like it was 2021,
I did the research and in a 2023
I discovered that I might do even
greater things with a different
techniques and with a different
technologies and the data.
>> would be this would be kind of like if
someone found request smuggling
kind of before before someone else did
and then was like using it on targets.
It's like a new vulnerability class kind
of. Yeah, that that was definitely the
class.
So, I did the disclosure for a few
private programs just to verify my my
theory and how that happened and how
impactful it is. And I still have this
like classification on my HackerOne
profile in a private where some money is
accumulated to that classification,
which is kind of interesting.
So, I did the verification for 10 maybe
reports on the platform.
Discussed that vulnerability not the
vulnerability, attack vector with one of
the top hacker one
hackers. He He's I think in the first uh
five
um positions in hacker one leaderboard
uh even on those days and even right
now. So, that's a trusted guy. And we
discussed with him like about that about
the what can happen and how can we
verify? How can we submit this?
But, submitting this on that time was
kind of hard and you might be punished
quite well. Like, nobody noticed that
it's a like it's a the
the problem itself, not just you're
doing something bad against other
organizations. Um so, yeah. The time spy
I changed from the period a few places.
Um and I landed in the organization
where we do our program management.
Like, we have the program, we have the
scope, we have the applications. And I
did this research against our own
organization. Uh just to verify that we
are kind of secure and did all
>> Uh I'm in SEMrush and you mentioned
before the SEMrush is
>> No, I'm I'm saying that that's where you
did it. That's where you like uh
right now this part of the story, that's
where you saying you tested it
internally. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, it
was verified internally. So, and I even
did a few talks uh within the
organization saying like, "Look, that's
the attack vector
uh that is kind of bad and we need to to
make some like protection mechanisms in
place." And we did this.
Uh I did education part for the security
team for the for the
um
employees and we kind of came with this.
Um and yeah, after the 3 years
I got the report from the hacker one and
it started with the words and with the
links as I did 3 years ago. Like
like completely like even like the
commas, the the
the words itself, like, it's replicated
100%.
And I was like
>> So, just just just just to clarify for
the listeners, basically,
Kvetko, 3 years ago, submitted something
to like 10 bug bounty platform or or
sorry, 10 bug bounty programs. He puts
in like 10 reports. Then, literally,
like a like a was a month ago or 2
months ago,
for the program he manages, he receives
a report that was word-for-word his,
including comma for comma, period for
period,
uh the thing that he had basically
reported 3 years ago.
Yeah, and I was really sad because not
that the the the attack surface that
attack vector was exposed. I think it
it's well known right now, like, and
some people knew about this, some people
knew about how it happening and why it's
so,
but I was sad about that the work I did,
the words I placed word by word,
explaining everything with the link,
with the reference about that. It leaked
to the
>> and the the word the words were also,
sorry to cut you off, the words were
also like, "I did this research." So,
like, not only was this person stealing
your report, but they were also claiming
to do research they didn't do? That's
hilarious. So, I was like, kind of,
"Okay, let's put away my emotion." Like,
let's ask that guy as a program manager,
"Where did you get this?" Like, and ask
him, like, "Dude, where did you get
this?"
And he like replied to me saying, "Oh,
that's that's the ChatGPT help me with
this." I was like, "No way." Like,
"Okay, let let me try if my research,
like, 3 years ago leaked to the LLM
models with the word by word, and if
they can give me back this, I can
believe you, right?" So, I tried. I
tried 10 times.
Nothing worked. I can't get back the
same words as the guy did. So, But was
clearly like he's he got this from
somewhere.
And I was really like
in a question again saying, "Dude, like
I I knew that it it's not ChatGPT. Like
share me like the story." And he was
like
>> you Did Did you say that at the end or
did you reach out to HackerOne first?
Like how how deep how deep did you go
questioning the reporter before you just
went to HackerOne?
I didn't try to blame the hacker. I
didn't try to make the my my own
investigation against that guy.
Uh and I knew that that guy might be
just one guy. He might found that
somewhere.
Uh and I and I checked his statistics.
His statistics started like a year and a
half. So it it wasn't clear like was he
the first one?
So
um I immediately raised the the
mediation report to the HackerOne
saying, "Look, like that's the stolen
research before and it was never
published somewhere." An important part
was I never published this on on purpose
because I was like afraid of magnitude
of the problem that might happen with
other organizations and companies if I
will share this publicly.
So Yeah, the way that you the way that
you talked about it at your work, it
sounds like it's kind of like not a
super easy fix. Like you need to come up
with some like mitigations or strategies
for it, right? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And if
I will just expose this Pandora box to
everyone, yeah, I might be just the one
the first guy who will be on blame about
that problem on all the companies around
Uh I wasn't happy about this. So I kept
that as a secret. Uh so the guy replied
to me back saying, "No. No. Like that's
100% ChatGPT." I was like, "Dude, like
that's that's horrible. Like you're
doing horrible things. You're stealing
the the word-by-word report. Even
started with like I'm doing this
research. Like you never did this. Like
what are you talking about?" Uh
so yeah, I shared all the things to the
HackerOne. And to my surprise, HackerOne
did quite well investigation, and I
think I might say this that they
discovered multiple people used this,
um, as a template. Uh, they first said
it's it's a stolen template, but it's
hard to say that it's just a template.
It was like the pure research explained
well, and like somebody who have zero
clue about that might just replicate and
get some money. It's like it's not a
template, it's kind of research.
Um, yeah.
So, they did investigation, and, um,
they found that that might be leaked not
from the HackerOne triage team, uh, but
could be leaked from the customers, I
would say. Um, yeah, 100% uh, I'm not
surprised about that. And could be
leaked from the, um,
collaborators, uh, who joined the
initial report, uh, because they submit
the duplicate one.
And that story is kind of
kind of shady, um,
and it's difficult to protect your,
like, um, intellectual property.
>> Yeah, in that story.
Uh, but it gave me some insights about
that story as well, and I'm really like
curious, uh,
and I'm really happy to share this with
you because it might be important to
other hackers like to think twice before
making the report so much clearer just
to
to express someone just to make some
bonuses maybe for the for the very clear
report, I don't know. Uh, so, yeah, the
the intellectual property might be
exposed from the customers because I saw
the organization where, the
it was not my organization, and it's not
mine at moment, but the friend
organization was connected with a Slack
channel to the HackerOne platform. So,
when the researcher is submitting the
finding, it's going to their Slack
channel.
Uh and that Slack channel was publicly
accessible to all employees, not just
for the security team. And you can
control managers from marketing team.
You can control like other people that
is have no ideas what it is, but they
just can copy this, right? They can
think like, "Okay, that's interesting.
Let me share this with my husband or
with my friend, for example, right?" So,
you can't really control this and keep
this
as a secret.
And yeah, the second part is the when
the collaborator joining the initial
report uh because he made the submission
the duplicate, that collaborator can
expose the change that you made, even if
the final report might make by well, but
the technique might be exposed. And
that's the part that is like extremely
important, and I think that
HackerOne should shouldn't allow program
managers and the triagers to allow to
join the newcomers to the initial report
without acceptance from the initial
hacker. If the hacker is okay to share
this, yeah, that's okay. If the hacker
is not happy about this to share with
everybody,
um yeah, I think it it shouldn't work
like this. Like because right now you
can you can put this guy to the main
report, and he can chase to something
that was crucial for you.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Yeah, it's really
weird.
I feel like I've always been on the
other side of it. Like I
I don't know. I feel like my reports
don't get duped on very much, but I've
duped on other people's reports, and I'm
always frustrated. Like just let me see
the report because then I can verify if
this is a real duplicate or not, right?
Like I want to be able to verify myself
whether it's a duplicate. And then now,
all of a sudden after the story, I'm
like, "Oh, it makes so much sense why
they don't just let people be joined."
Cuz like all of those people who, you
know, get duped to it, one,
if it if their report wasn't a
duplicate, they just got access to your
report for no reason. And sometimes they
are wrong, right? So, maybe they got
added to your report and you lost your
intellectual property and they didn't
even submit the same bug. It was some
other random bug, right? But then even
if they did submit something similar,
they still get your full explanation,
right? Maybe you're a much better report
writer. Maybe you have other escalation
paths in your report that they didn't
have. And so, anyways, now I'm very
sympathetic to that. I still think, like
you said, there should be some sort of
way to like request access to that first
report and if the first hacker doesn't
care, then it's like who cares.
And I also think that HackerOne and
other bug bounty programs should
definitely
allow the report title to often be like
verified because sometimes that'll give
you enough information to know if it's
like actually a dupe or not.
But yeah, I I was I was thinking about
this and I was chatting with AI about
just like this whole situation. And I
feel like I you know, there's like a
couple takeaways. One is, like you said,
maybe don't over detail your reports.
You know, like you need to put enough
details to replicate it, but maybe don't
explain like, "Hey, I was doing this
research and I found these other things
because, you know, you might be giving
away your thought process or more bugs
than you even, you know, mean to."
Another thing is like run exploits
through like your server instead of
third-party services or like set up your
own Burp Collab, that sort of thing.
Then yeah, definitely don't disclose
like don't automatically add dupe
reporters to your thing. And then one
thing, I don't know if you mentioned
this or if it's something that like I
wrote down, but I think it'd be kind of
cool and I think some people do do this,
but just like have some sort of like
watermark or hidden watermark in your
reports. Like
>> Yeah, that's I mentioned this as a like
as a final thoughts about the story in
the HackerOne private channel saying
look like that's kind of the story why I
would like to keep my secret as a secret
without exposing the entire chain of
like making the account, making some
change of the bugs to be as a RC.
Because
it's meant to be the code execution. So
fix this. You shouldn't care about the
the part of the chain that I made or
like some small part of the chains that
is important for myself. Yeah, I saw I
even saw as a program manager when some
people doing the
vulnerability submission and they giving
you the ability to replicate that
complex bug through their own server
without exposing the binaries, without
exposing the the process of making that
exploit.
Yeah, valid.
That that
back on the time when I saw this I was
like, "Dude, like why don't you share
with me this? Like I need to replicate
this." And now I was like, "Okay, that's
the reason." Like I I don't know the the
same next. Yeah, and and over detailing
the report it might be like the problem
in the future.
And regarding the watermarks, like I was
such a lucky person to see
my report after the three years word by
word. But what the guy if was like a bit
smart
just to change the wordings, just to
change everything. He he found the
the attack vector, right? But he was
smart to to hide this to make as his
own.
That dude wasn't smart. But in that
story I think in the in the crucial
words maybe or in the crucial links or
the part of the exploit you might put
something that can identify you as the
owner of that information. Maybe putting
some mistakes in the word, putting the
words in a different language where you
can verify that, "Okay, Google
translate, please translate this word."
And it it's not translatable because the
word the letter in the middle is like
from the different language.
But after all, you might verify that
okay, that mine and where did you get
it? I have no idea. Let's figure out. So
I think that watermarks kind of the
the important stuff and I even shared
this idea with the hacker one because
they should secure the reports from
triages as well.
So yeah,
the triages is also
I had two cool ways we could do that.
One is like
invisible Unicode tags, like the stuff
that you know is kind of cool for AI and
then the other thing is like just zero
width characters.
You could like you know pepper those in
certain places and then the other cool
thing about it is like the bug bounty
platforms should be able to like grep
across or search across all the reports
for that string just so I can
immediately know if it was used
elsewhere, you know.
I guess it would have to be like a super
user who could do that cuz
there's not very many people with access
to every program, but
but yeah, that'd be really interesting.
Did they tell you how how many other
companies they had reported it to or
anything?
I knew the the amount of the hackers
that was identified with my template
and it's more than five
but less than 10.
And I I tried to to push this story
forward saying look like what if these
guys might be discovered later in life
hacking event and if they did that
shitty things before, they might do this
shitty things during the event. So I
would like to have them like kind of
punished saying like okay, they they
broke the rules of the code of conduct
at least. So do something with this
because because of this they will not be
invited in the future.
As hacker one says like they did this
violation of the code of conduct for the
hackers. So I'm okay with this and that
story might be the lesson for for those
who might have the intellectual property
in their own screen
and they're thinking about using this.
Well, like some days it might be exposed
and you will find yourself in a shitty
situation and just measure your like
name and the profit that you might gain
like that's question like and I will not
do any dirty things against different
interesting techniques because I do
value my my name like I don't want to
find myself in a trouble in the future.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's true. You know, it's kind
of tough also.
I'm not standing up for the for the bad
guys, but I like for the hackers that
did that, but you know, it's also one of
those situations where maybe one or two
of those first people that got access to
it said like this is my template. As
they sent it to the second and third and
fourth and fifth and sixth, you know,
and so they feel like they have
permission from the first person, but
the first person actually stole it, you
know, it's like man, these sort of
situations are really tough.
Yeah, that's true.
But such an irony like seeing my report
started with the same words as I did 3
years ago. It was like such a joke.
Oh, yeah, seriously.
All right, dude. Well, we can wrap it
here. I really really appreciate you
coming on. Did you have any other things
that you wanted to mention or shout out
like either your company or your program
or your socials or anything that you
wanted to mention?
Oh, yeah.
We do the human validation on the
hackerone. We don't reply with the with
the buzz words with the predefined
templates and we do the the good
investigation against each of the report
with the with the severity evaluations
well and with the business impact. So,
we're not really dumb. Me as a hacker I
treat other hackers as I want
to be treated. So, yeah, feel free to
submit some bugs on the Semrush program.
That's a public program on the
hackerone.
We do pay still quite well.
We are kind of in the transition of the
business transformations soon.
You will find out maybe later in the
news.
But so far we have a program. We do our
security as as as best as possible. And
yeah, if you find something cool and
interesting critical
or even if it's
outside of the scope or even like at
least connected to our brand and to our
organization,
we do evaluation. We don't like do that
stuff as like other programs might might
make you saying like okay, we have a
scope. That's out of scope. That's not
counted. That's informative that not
counted. We really value each report and
trying to figure out is it like
impactful for the business? Do we need
to pay for this or not? Yeah.
Awesome. Well, thank you. Yeah, so go
hack on on Semrush. Go follow Krevetsko
on social. It's
k r e v e t k o and then his name
Valery, but you'll find it if you look
it up. He's got lots of bug bounty
followers so it should pop up for you
guys. Thank you so much for coming on
today, brother.
Thank you for the invitation. It was a
really amazing opportunity. I can't
still imagine that you just invited me.
Like who I am? I'm just a random hacker.
Uh
Justin said he wanted to have you on
already in the past so it's our
pleasure. Appreciate it. Thank you.
Peace. Have a nice day.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more Critical Thinking content or if you
want to support the show, head over to
ctb.show/discord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great high-level hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hack alongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.